Guide to the Department of Italian, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Italian, Yale University, records
1931-1988
RU 762
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
(6 boxes)
The records consist of films, grade sheets, budgets and accounting records, and general office files documenting students, faculty, staff and curricula of the Yale Department of Italian.
Yale University. Department of Italian
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of films, grade sheets, budgets and accounting records, and general office files documenting students, faculty, staff and curricula of the Yale Department of Italian.
Italian language -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Motion pictures (visual works); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of Italian
- Records, circa 1973-1988; Accession 1990-A-126
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Lab Schedule, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Films, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Senior Search, General, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New Job (Hiring), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Returned Senior Position Applications
  - Porta (miscellaneous), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Senior Search, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Answers to Circular Letter, 1980 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Della Terza, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Procaccini (personal), 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Freccero (personal), 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Apfelbaum (personal), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ballerini (personal), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Furio Colombo, 1977 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brose (personal), 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bertolini (personal), 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Valesio (personal), 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Eco (personal), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brown-Yale-Bologna Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence to Valesio, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Departmental- miscellaneous, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Literature Major Search, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Junior Search, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Departmental- miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ruggiero- correspondenza da riportare, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ruggiero student papers, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Grade sheets, 1987- 1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Work postponement requests, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Alverez, Brandy L., "Hercules and the Labor of History in Vico's New Science", 1988 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ruggiero final exams, 1987- 1988 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous xeroxed material, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Chron, Chairman, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Chron, Chairman, Fall 1979 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Chron, Chairman, Spring 1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Fido (visiting faculty), 1975 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Vattimo, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Della Terza, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Shapiro (personal), 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Lectures, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Administration, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Administration, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Expense Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Administration, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Fantanella, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Lectures, Fall 1980 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Lectures, Fall 1979 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Santagata Lecture, 1980 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Shapiro Lecture, 1980 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Arbasina Lecture, 1980 April 29 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - G. Mazzotta Lecture, 1979 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Literature 140- Umberto Eco, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Faculty staffing, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Faculty staffing, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Faculty staffing, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Personnel Profile Forms, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Personnel Profile Forms, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Student Teaching, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Student Teaching (salaries), 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Student Teaching (assignments), 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Student Teaching, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Student Teaching, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Students (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Budget
    - 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Administration, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Eco (Visiting Faculty)
  - Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Eco (miscellaneous), 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Valesio, Final Papers, Spring 1988 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Chron: DGS, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Public Relations, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Chron Chairman, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Financial Aid, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Financial Aid, 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Chron, Chairman, Fall 1984 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Valesio: Inactive Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Receipts, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Fascism symposium, 1984 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Lectures, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Master Keyforms, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Accounting Transfers
  - Expense Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Expense Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Teaching Fellows, Spring 1986 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Teaching Fellows, Fall 1984 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Teaching Fellows, Fall 1985 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Teaching Fellows, Spring 1985 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Printing Service, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Silvia's Weekly Time Cards, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Wall Copy Center, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Silvia's Time Cards, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Stock Request, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Foreign Students and Scholars, undated (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Odd addresses, schedules, library loan cards, depression, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Student Research Appointment, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Gifts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Request for leave of absence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Stencils, undated (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Inquiries, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Silvia's Inactive Time Cards, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Office of Foreign Students/Scholars Information, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Telephone, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Typing, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Conference Information, 1980 October 31 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Alterations Request Forms, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Stamp Request Forms, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Tutors, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Travel/Moving expenses, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Budget-Archives, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Scheduled Classroom Hours, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Courses and Addresses, 1976-1982 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Rainbow Budget Sheets, 1981-1984 (Box 4)
  - Bursary Payroll, 1980-1984
- Records, circa 1972-1984; Accession 1992-A-032
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Graduate School Bulletin, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Renaissance Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Degrees Granted, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Recommendation - To Be Written, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Job Openings, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Evaluations, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Telephone Authorization Cards, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Space Allocation, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Roman Philology, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - YaleUniversityCouncil, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Leave Policy, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Employment - Bursary, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Grade Cards, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Personnel Attendance Records, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Student Grade Cards, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Vitae - Graduate Students, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Transcripts, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Registrations, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Graduate Students - Sixth Year Extensions, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Registration, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Transcripts, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Italian Department Regulations, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Admissions, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Graduate Admissions, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Financial Aid - Current Students, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Graduate Admissions and Financial Aid, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Admissions, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Graduate Admissions, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Graduate Admissions and Current Student Aid, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Graduate Students - Admissions - Declines, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - D'Egidio, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mazzotta's Publications - Paolo's Copies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Grades, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Valesio Grades, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Mazzotta Replies, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 44 - 45)
  - Course Evaluations Fall, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Salary Raise Information, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - New Appointments, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - General Administration, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - New Appointments, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 51 - 52)
  - Administration, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 53 - 54)
  - T.A.'s Personnel Profile, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Transcripts, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Teaching Appointments, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Memorandum on course and exam for Italian 41 and 105, 1931-1932; Accession 1994-A-099
  - Memorandum on course and exam for Italian 41 and 105, 1931-1932 (Box 1)